Simply put, this combination of elements could allow us to cyberform entire worlds.
简单的说 这种化合物可以让我们数字化整个世界
Eh... why do I feel a Shockwave plan coming on?
哎…貌似震荡波又在琢磨什么蹩脚的计划了
Kah... oh
啊…噢
Do not think for a moment, Starscream.
红蜘蛛 别以为你险些让我 落入汽车人手中的事就这么完了
Aah. Master? Are you going to allow one lieutenant to harm another?
啊 主人？难道您就任由您的一个副官去伤害另一个？
Master?
主人？！
I'm thinking.
我在考虑呢…
I am tempted to force you to share my perception of things.
我准备让你也体验一下独眼的感觉
No! I only did what I thought was best for the mission.
不！我那么做完全是为了任务着想
But I do feel compelled to add that it was my very error
但我必须补充一下 发生这个小意外
in judgment that made this happy accident possible!
确实是因为我的重大失误！
If I recollect, you were seeking to purge your laboratory of sensitive materials before the Autobots arrived.
我当时并不知道你想在汽车人 到达之前销毁实验室的敏感数据
Were you not?
你怎么看？
Your argument... is logical.
你的解释…符合逻辑
Exemplary teamwork. Now tell me, Shockwave.
多么融洽的团队精神 告诉我 震荡波
Why does this cyber-matter resemble chaos?
为何这种物质生长得如此混乱？
The basic elements are apparently unstable,
很明显 其基础元素仍不稳定
I will turn my attention to correcting that.
我会集中精力解决这个问题
Ah... nevertheless, should we use this cyber-matter to restore Cybertron,
嗯 但是 无论是用这种物质恢复塞博特恩
or cyberform earth, we would require a launch mechanism, would we not?
或是数字化地球 都需要某种启动装置 是吧？
Then we will focus all our remaining resources
那我们就先集中手头的所有资源
upon the successful reconstruction of the Omega Lock.
全力修复终极之锁吧
I've done everything I can.
我已经尽我所能了
Considering the limitations of my equipment,
鉴于我缺乏趁手的设备
and less than ideal spare parts.
以及合适的配件
It remains uncertain if Ultra Magnus's new appendage will be fit for battle...
目前我们仍无法确定 通天晓的假肢是否适合战斗…
though it should prove functional,
不过经过足够的物理治疗
after the requisite amount of therapy.
它应该能发挥一定的作用
That is all we can hope for, old friend.
也只能希望如此了 老朋友
You doing okay?
你没事吧？
I'm still two-fisted.
至少两只手都还在
So's Magnus.
通天晓也是
Wait and see, the claw's gonna become his signature...
等着瞧吧 这爪子将会成为他的标志性象征
You know, like the way you own that voice box Ratchet slapped in your throat!
你明白的 就像救护车塞到你喉咙里的那个发声器！
I mean, you know, everyone understands you fine!
嗯…我是说 大家完全能听懂你说的话！
Why would you even consider getting it fixed now, am I right?
何必还总想着去修复它呢 对吧？
Whoa, what'd he say?
哇噢 他说什么？
Bee's kind of still attached to the sound of his own voice...
小蜂还是很想找回自己的声音
His original one.
他原本的声音
Hey, look at the bright, shiny side,
嘿 看看好的一面
Commander Magnus and Jackie single-handedly put the kibosh on project Predacon.
通天晓指挥官和老千稍一出手 就让巨狰狞计划变成一纸空谈了
Though at least one beast that we know of remains...
但就我们所知 至少还有一只野兽仍存活于世
The one who has demonstrated the ability to transform.
并且具有变形能力
Predaking, we will soon plot our strike against the Autobots,
冲云霄 我们很快就会策划对汽车人的进攻
to punish them for the massacre of your kind.
要让他们为对你族群的恶行付出代价
While I fully intend to exact my revenge,
我非常期待能手刃仇家
Project Predacon was merely a squadron,
但巨狰狞计划只不过试图打造一支小队
not an army.
而非一支大军
I see...
我明白…
My liege, if you truly aspire to restore our home world,
我的君王 如果您真的渴望恢复我们的家园
Then I have every faith that you will resurrect the entirety of the Predacon race
那么 我有充足的信心 您将通过残留于塞博特恩的骸骨
from the remains which lie there,
复活整个巨狰狞种族
So that I may lead them against any and all of our shared enemies.
这样我就可以带领他们 抗击我们共同的任何敌人
We salvaged much of the wreckage of the Omega Lock.
我们已搜集到终极之锁的大部分残骸
But the damage was quite severe.
但它们都已严重受损
I would urge the selective use of earth technology,
我恳请选择性地使用地球技术
Retro-fitting its operating systems will be more efficient than rebuilding from scratch.
改造其操作系统 这样比重新建造要更有效率
Then do provide Starscream with your wish list.
那么也要让红蜘蛛物尽其用
Since Shockwave must turn his attention to the stabilization of our Cyber-matter,
由于震荡波将投身于稳定塞博特恩网状物的研究之中
you will be in charge of acquisitions.
你就去负责搜集工作吧
Prime! We have trouble brewing.
擎天柱！我们又有麻烦了
The Cons staged a smash-and-grab at the Los Alamos nuclear plant late last night,
虎子们昨天深夜袭击了洛斯阿拉莫斯核电站
and made off with 20 tons of control rods.
并抢走了二十吨反应堆控制棒
What are the Decepticons looking to build?
霸天虎们到底想要建造什么？
Lord Megatron.
威震天陛下
I have determined that the synthetic energon formula provided by Knockout is the source of the instability.
我已确认 由击倒提供的 合成能量就是导致不稳定的根源
Simply because it is incomplete.
原因是其配方还不完整
Then make haste and complete it.
那么 尽快将其补充完整
We will not only require enough Cyber-matter to rebuild one planet,
因为我们不只需要足够的网状物来重建一颗星球
But to remake a second.
还需要用其改造另一颗
Master, excuse my impudence.
主人 恕我冒昧
But what is the logic behind ruling two worlds?
但统治两个世界是否符合逻辑？
It has taken me quite some time to fully comprehend
我过了很久才意识到
that Earth and Cybertron have always been linked, two halves of one whole,
地球与塞博特恩一直是紧密相连的
And that, to rule only one,
所以 只得到其中之一
Would be to never truly rule either.
无异于同时失去了两个
Prime!
擎天柱！
It's Cons again In progress this time.
虎子又露头了 而且被我们抓了个正着
Coordinates received, Agent Fowler.
坐标已收到 福勒探员
Let's roll!
出发！
Yip-yip!
慢着 慢着！
Your ability to roll remains predicated upon further exploration of your manual dexterity.
我还要继续检测你的手部灵敏度 才能决定你是否适合执行任务
I'm afraid that Ratchet's authority supersedes my own in medical matters.
在医疗事项上 恐怕救护车比我更有发言权
Eh... understood.
唉…我明白
Wow!
哇噢!
Ratchet, reopen the groundbridge.
救护车 打开环陆桥
But ensure that the humans are kept at a safe distance,
但要保证人类在安全距离以外
For we will be returning with a Decepticon prisoner.
因为我们要带回一个霸天虎俘虏
Because we had the foresight to shield our new base
得益于我们的先见之明 基地已被护盾笼罩了
our captive will be unable to transmit his coordinates to the decepticon warship.
我们的俘虏无法给霸天虎战舰发送坐标
Nor will they, in turn, be able to pinpoint his location.
反过来说 战舰也无法锁定他的位置
Guess we have all the time in the world to make Mr. Personality tell us everything he knows.
看来我们有足够的时间 让闷骚先生吐露心声了
The Con's veillance chief must know a lot, right?
虎子的监控主管一定知道不少内幕吧？
But Soundwave doesn't speak...
但声波不会说话…
Does he?
是吧？
I'm not sure he even has a face.
我都不确定他是不是有脸
With Laserbeak unable to triangulate Soundwave's current location,
鉴于激光鸟无法定位声波的位置
Are you not concerned about what our comrade might spill?
您就不担心我们这位同僚会把什么都招了？
Of one thing, I'm certain.
有一点 我可以确认
Soundwave knows when to impart information,
声波很清楚何时该开口
And when to withhold it.
何时该闭嘴
Why is Megatron stealing human technology?
威震天为何要窃取人类科技？
What is he attempting to build?
他究竟打算建造什么？
Wwwhy is MMegatron stealing human ttechnology?
威…威…威震天为何要窃取人类科…科…科技？
Wwwhat is he attempting tto build?
他…他…他到底打算建造什…什…么？
Wow, Optimus Prime: the remix!
哇哦 混音版擎天柱啊！
Oh, yeah? Why don't I wipe that smile right off his face.
小子很狂啊？让我把他的笑脸变成哭脸！
Soundwave, we have treated you fairly.
声波 我们对你已经很客气了
For the sake of the natives of this planet,
为了这颗星球的居民着想
tell us what Megatron is attempting to build,
告诉我们威震天究竟要建造什么？
Before we are forced to rely upon less civil methods of interrogation.
不然我们就必须采用一些非常规的审讯手段了
Scrap this!
别浪费时间了！
Soundwave is no ordinary Cybertronian, inside or out,
声波从里到外都不是一个正常的塞博特恩人
So I would strongly suggest opening him up
所以我强烈建议把他开膛破肚
so we can have a first-hand look at the information recorded on his drives.
先仔细研究一下他硬盘上的数据
Ah-oh.
啊哦
All right, he's downloading data.
行了 他在下载数据
No. Soundwave is erasing data.
不 声波在删除数据
Soundwave superior. Autobots inferior.
声波优越 汽车人低劣 （86大电影台词）
Is he...?
他是不是…？
His vital signs remain functional.
他的主要功能仍在运作
It seems he has simply severed all communications,
似乎只是切断了所有的通讯功能
by crashing his own drives.
通过破坏自己的硬盘
Lord Megatron.
威震天陛下
I have located the one item upon this world which possesses
我已经找到了这个世界上唯一一个
enough raw tonnage to power the reconstructed Omega Lock.
具有足够的原始能量来驱动重铸的终极之锁的物体
A Particle Collider's Synchrotron.
一台粒子同步对撞机
Excellent, Shockwave.
非常好 震荡波
However, the successful completion of the synthetic energon formula
但是 完善合成能量配方的难度 远在我的预期之上
Knockout first procured this unfinished shamble from the Autobot medic,
击倒从汽车人的医生那里获取了这个未完成配方
did he not?
不是么？
That is my understanding.
我也是这么理解的
Then the most efficient means to an end
那么最快的解决办法 就是将那名医生弄到手
Attempting to abduct the one Autobot who rarely leaves their base...
试图绑架一个几乎寸步不离基地的汽车人…
a base we have yet to locate.
而且也不知道他们基地的位置
May prove to be a challenge.
…这可有点不好办啊
You forget that we currently have an agent within the Autobot base.
你忘了 我们的人现在正在汽车人的基地里
Laserbeak could reconnect with Soundwave,
激光鸟可以重新与声波建立连接
And upload his directive to him.
并将指令上传给他
Which would still require knowing the location of their base.
但这仍需要找到他们的基地
It is my understanding that Soundwave kept surveillance records of more than just the human children.
我猜声波的监控记录可不只包括那些孩子
Prime! These recent Con heists have general bryce breathing down my neck.
擎天柱！最近这些虎子的 抢劫案让布莱斯将军把我盯得很紧
So I gotta get back to the barbecue today for another grilling.
我今天还得回炉去被烤个外焦里嫩
Understood, Agent Fowler.
明白 福勒探员
And rest assured, should our prisoner return online,
请放心 一旦我们的俘虏清醒过来
We will resume our interrogation.
我们会立即继续对他进行审讯
Sounds like a plan.
听起来不错
I'll get back to base as soon as possible.
我会尽快赶回基地
You summoned me, Lord Megatron.
您召见我 威震天陛下
I require your services,
我需要你做一件事
since we anticipate an Autobot presence at our next event.
我们已预料到汽车人 会对我们的下一次行动进行干预
I welcome any opportunity to face the Prime again,
我非常期待能再次面对擎天柱
warrior to warrior.
来一场战士间的对决
You pride yourself on your evolution,
你对自己的进化沾沾自喜
Yet you have learned nothing!
但见识却毫无长进！
I may have lost my surveillance chief today.
我可能已经失去了我的监控主管
The Autobots have expanded their forces, while ours continue to dwindle.
汽车人已经壮大了自己的队伍 而我们却日渐萎靡
Then I shall simply battle twice as fiercely.
那么我会以双倍的努力投入战斗
As a beast!
还得像个野兽一样！
I'm on my way to the base
我正在赶回基地
but I just got word.
但我收到了一个消息
The Cons busted into the Solaris Particle Collider Project at the south pole.
虎子们袭击了位于南极的索拉力粒子对撞机工程
Autobots.
汽车人
Wha--? Yip-yip--
啥？慢着 慢着…
Doc, the Commander's ready.
大夫 指挥官已经准备好了
Oh... Fine, fine...
唉 好吧 好吧
Bulkhead, Smokescreen,
隔板 烟幕
remain here with Ratchet to guard our prisoner.
和救护车一起留在这里 看守犯人
Every one else, transform and roll out!
其他人 变形出发！
Can't we throw a tarp over him?
能不能找块布把他遮起来？
He's creeping me out.
他让我直起鸡皮疙瘩
Yeah. It's like he's watching,
没错 无论你从哪个方向看
no matter where you go.
他都好像在盯着你
Would both of you stop focusing on what Soundwave can or cannot see
你们俩能不能别再纠结声波的眼睛问题
and help me figure out what he did not tell?
帮我想想他到底隐瞒了什么？
Like why Megatron would be interested in something believed to generate enough power
比如威震天为何对一台能量 大到能制造出黑洞的机器感兴趣？
Black holes?
黑洞吗？
So Megatron's looking to swallow up the known universe.
那可能是威震天想吞噬整个宇宙
And everything in it.
以及宇宙里的一切
No, no.
不对 不对！
He would merely want to harness the power of something capable of swallowing worlds.
他仅仅是想借助这种可以吞噬宇宙的力量
In order to... create one.
用来…创造某物
Oh my...
哦 天啊…
Optimus, I know this hardly seems the time... but it may aid you in your task.
擎天柱 我知道现在时机不妥 但这条信息可能有助于你的任务
Go ahead.
说吧
I believe that Megatron may be attempting to rebuild the Omega Lock.
我相信威震天试图重铸终极之锁
Do we let him?
我们是不是任由他这么做？
No. For you know as well as I...
不 你我都心知肚明
that Megatron will use a reconstructed lock to Cyberform both Cybertron and Earth.
威震天会使用终极之锁同时数字化塞博特恩和地球
And that is one abuse of power that we cannot allow.
我们不能容忍这种暴行
Awh... understood.
唉 明白了
Down!
快闪开!
The Decepticons must not be allowed to secure their target.
一定不能让霸天虎得逞！
I will engage the Predacon.
我来对付这只巨狰狞
You heard your leader. Forge ahead.
你们都听到领袖的命令了 继续前进！
Yaah!
呀!
Wha!
哇！
Yaah!
呃！
Woah!
喔啊！
Somebody knew we were coming!
他们知道我们会来！
You think?
还用说?
Ratchet, it may not be with the forge or the Omega Lock,
救护车 即使不用卓天越之锤或者终极之锁
but we're gonna find a way to get our planet repaired.
我们也一定会找到办法来修复家园的
Oh, no!
噢 不！
Ah!
啊！
Heh!?
嗯？！
Yah... Dah...!
呀…啊
Eh...
呃…
Yaah!
呀！
Eh... eh... oh...
呃！呃…哦！
Aah!
啊！
Oh...
噢…